https://www.njstatelib.org/privacy-policy/

Skip to main content
connecting people with information through libraries
SEARCH
1. We respect your privacy
The New Jersey State Library (NJSL) respects your right to privacy and this policy sets out how we collect and treat your personal information.
“Personal information” is information we hold which is identifiable as being about you.
2. What personal information we collect
We may collect the following types of personal information from you:
3. How we collect your personal information
We collect personal information from you in a variety of ways, including: when you interact with us electronically or in person; when you access our website; and when we provide our services to you.
4. Use of your personal information
We use your information to provide our service to you. We also use it to improve our service and to notify you of opportunities that we think you might be interested in.
We do not provide your information to third parties, except that we may provide your information to our business partners who assist us in the provision of our services to you.
5. Security of your personal information
We take reasonable steps to protect your personal information. However we are not liable for any unauthorized access to this information.
6. Access to your personal information
You can access and update your personal information by contacting us at marketing@njstatelib.org.
7. Information Collected and Stored Automatically
When you visit our site, we may also collect and store the following information:
1. The Internet domain and IP address from which you access our site;
2. The date and time you access our site;
3. The pages you visit; and
4. If you linked to us from another site, the address of that site.
The New Jersey State Library uses this information to help make the site more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to the site and the types of technology visitors use.
8. Complaints about privacy
If you have any complaints about our privacy practices, please feel free to contact us with details of your complaints. We take complaints very seriously and will respond shortly after receiving notice of your complaint.
9. Changes
Please be aware that we may change this Privacy Policy in the future. The revised versions will be uploaded onto our website, so please check back from time to time.
10. Website
When you visit our website
When you come on to our website we may collect certain information such as browser type, operating system, website visited immediately before coming to our site, etc. This information is used in an aggregated manner to analyze how people use our site, such that we can improve our service. More information regarding the use of the Website can be found in our Terms & conditions.
Cookies
As is very common for companies, we use cookies on our website. Cookies are very small files which a website uses to identify you when you come back to the site and to store details about your use of the site. Cookies are not malicious programs that access or damage your computer. We use cookies to improve the experience of people using our website. More information on our use of Cookies can be found in our Cookie Policy.
Third party sites
Our site has links to other websites not owned or controlled by us. We are not responsible for these sites or the consequences of you going on to those sites.
Research LibraryAsk a Librarian
About Our Collections
eBooks and Audiobooks
Funding Information Center
Genealogy and Local History
General Book Collection
General Reference
Jerseyana Collection
Didn’t Find What You Were Looking For?
Does It Circulate?
How Do I Find … ?
New Jersey African American History Curriculum Guide: Grades 9 to 12
Unit 1 African Beginnings
Unit 2 Africa, Europe, and the Rise of Afro-America, 1441-1619
Unit 3 African American Slavery in the Colonial Era, 1619-1775
Unit 4 Blacks in the Revolutionary Era, 1776-1789
Unit 5 Slavery and AboliItion in Post-Revolutionary and Antebellum America, 1790-1960
Unit 6 African Americans and the Civil War, 1861-1865
Unit 7 The Reconstruction Era, 1865-1877
Unit 8 The Rise of Jim Crow and the Nadir, 1878-1915
Unit 9 World War I and the Great Migration, 1915-1920
Unit 10 Decade of the Twenties: From Great Migration to Great Depression
Unit 11 1930s: The Great Depression
Unit 12 World War II: Struggle for Democracy at Home and Abroad, 1940-1945
Unit 13 Immediate Postwar Years, 1945-1953
Unit 14 Civil Rights and Black Power Era: Gains and Losses, 1954-1970
Unit 15 Beyond Civil Rights, 1970-1994
Annual Report of the Inspector of Factories and Workshops
Bureau of Statistics of Labor and Industries Reports, 1878-1917
Corporations of New Jersey: List of Certificates to December 31, 1911
Forums Institute for Public Policy Issue Briefs
Morgan’s History of the New Jersey Conference of the A.M.E. Church, from 1872 to 1887…
Municipalities by County in New Jersey
New Jersey Constitutional Convention Proceedings – 1947
New Jersey in the American Revolution, 1763-1783: A Documentary History
New Jersey’s Revolutionary Experience
Official Register of the Officers and Men in the Revolutionary War
Interlibrary Loan Information for NJ Residents with a State Library Card: JerseyCat
Using ILLiad to Request Books and Articles: State Employees and TESU Staff, Students and Mentors
Photocopy Request Form for New Jersey and Out-of-State Residents
Braille & Audio Reading Download (BARD)
Services for LibrariesNew Jersey Library Construction Bond Act
Cross Cultural Communicators in Libraries Face-To-Face Training
Authors and Illustrators Born in or Associated with New Jersey
CONTACT Street Address:
185 W. State St.
Trenton, NJ 08608
Mailing Address:
P.O. Box 520
Trenton, NJ 08625
Phone: (609) 278-2640
Fax: (609) 278-2652
TALKING BOOK & BRAILLE CENTER Street Address:
2300 Stuyvesant Avenue
Trenton, NJ 08618
Mailing Address:
How Do I Find … ?
Braille and Audio Reading Download (BARD)
Authors and Illustrators Born in or Associated with New Jersey
